mutualofomaha.com 2015-12-06

# Privacy Policy - Mutual of Omaha

Mutual of Omaha Insurance Company and its affiliates (“Mutual of Omaha”) respects the privacy of visitors of mutualofomaha.com and all sites linking to this Privacy Policy (“Policy”)(collectively “sites”). This Policy explains how Mutual of Omaha collects, uses and shares information about you from our sites and the choices that you can make about the way your information is collected, used and shared. Mutual of Omaha encourages you to read this Policy and those of all web sites you visit.

In addition to this Policy, Mutual of Omaha’s written Privacy Notices further describe how we handle your personal information (defined below) shared with us, such as when you apply for or purchase our products and services. If you would like to view these Privacy Notices, please click on the appropriate link below:

  * Privacy Notices
  * HIPAA Notices
  * New York Domestic Violence

We encourage you to read our Policy before using the sites. By visiting our sites, you are agreeing in advance to the current and future terms of this Policy. If you do not wish to agree to these terms, you should leave this web site. Further, framing of our sites on other web sites is subject to the terms and policy practices of the framing web sites.

The following sections address mutualofomaha.com’s privacy issues in more detail:

  * This Policy applies to all services and sub-sites available under the domain [mutualofomaha.com](http://www.mutualofomaha.com/ "Mutual of Omaha"). We encourage you to read our Policy before using the site. By visiting this web site, you are agreeing in advance to the current and future terms of this Policy. If you do not wish to agree to these terms, you should leave this web site.

  * There are two types of information collected on our sites: Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information.

#### Personally Identifiable Information

Personally Identifiable Information (“personal information”) is information that identifies you as an individual, such as your name, mailing address, email address, date of birth, etc. Personal information is only obtained by us when you voluntarily provide the information to us. Mutual of Omaha does not collect, nor do we provide any other party with personal information from our sites’ visitors over time and across third party web sites.

#### Non-Personally Identifiable Information

Non-Personally Identifiable Information (“non-personal information”) is information that does not identify you as an individual, such as your browser type, IP Address, and the URL of the previous web site you visited. Mutual of Omaha may automatically collect certain types of non-personal information from you when you visit our sites. We may also collect non-personal information that you voluntarily provide, such as information included in response to a questionnaire or survey.

  * Mutual of Omaha uses personal information it collects on our sites to better understand your needs and interests and to provide you with products and services, and features that we believe better meet your needs or requests. We only collect information that we consider necessary for achieving these purposes. 

  * Mutual of Omaha collects on-line data when you provide information to us, such as through form submissions, or through the use of web technology.

#### Information Collected Through You

If you choose to use certain services on our sites, we may require you to provide contact and identity information. Ordinarily, we indicate which fields are required and which fields are optional. If you choose not to use a particular service or feature, you do not have to provide the requested contact or identity information.

#### Non-Personal Information Collected Through Technology

##### Cookies:

Our sites may use cookie technology to improve your experience and gather data for web site statistical reporting. Cookie technology does not capture your individual email address or any personal information about you.

A cookie is a small piece of information sent by a web site that is saved on your hard disk by your computer’s browser. It holds information a site may need to personalize your experience (i.e., rotating images on our sites’ home pages) and gathers web site statistical data, such as which pages are visited, what is downloaded, the Internet provider’s domain name and country that our visitors come from and the addresses of sites visited immediately before and after coming to our sites. However, none of this information is associated with you as an individual and is measured only in aggregate. Mutual of Omaha also uses cookies in conjunction with third party services to obtain demographic data on visitors to our sites. Examples of the data collected include data on your hobbies, interests and brand preferences. Although this information is associated with unique browsers, visitors’ identities remain anonymous to Mutual of Omaha.

Mutual of Omaha may use this demographic and interest data to obtain a better understanding of the persons that shop for and purchase our products and services, as well as to aid in producing relevant and effective on-line advertising. 

You can control how this information is gathered by us. To browse without cookies on our sites, configure your browser to reject all cookies or to notify you when a cookie is set. Each browser is different, so check the “Help” menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

##### IP Address:

Our sites may collect IP addresses for the purposes of systems administration, server problem diagnosis and compiling aggregate information, such as how many visitors accessed our sites. When you visit a particular web page on our sites, our servers log your IP address. An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer automatically when you use the Internet. We also collect IP addresses for authentication purposes when you submit on-line applications for our products and services.

##### Embedded Pixels: 

We may use embedded pixel technologies on selected pages for the purposes of identifying unique browser visits to our sites as opposed to aggregate hits. In addition, embedded pixels or other technologies may be used in emails to provide information on when the email was opened to track marketing campaign responsiveness. Information collected using these technologies may be associated with the recipient's email address.

  * In the normal course of business, we may share personal information you provide to us on our sites among Mutual of Omaha and its affiliated companies, including our banking affiliates. The type of information shared may include your name and other identifying information, as well as information about your transactions with us, such as your payment history.

We may also share your personal information with third parties outside Mutual of Omaha and its affiliated companies, such as: (a) with our agents and brokers; (b) to process an insurance transaction that you request; (c) to service your account, such as paying a claim; (d) with contractors, service providers and other third parties to support our business and perform functions on our behalf; and (e) with other parties with whom we have joint marketing agreements.

We do not share medical information you provide to us, except to the extent we are required or permitted to share such information under federal or state law.

#### Disclosure of personal information for legal purposes and protection of Mutual of Omaha and others: 

We also reserve the right to share your personal information with third parties if we believe such action is necessary in order to: (a) conform with the requirements of any court order, law or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request; (b) protect or defend our legal rights or property, our sites, or our users; or (c) investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person or violations of the terms and conditions of using our sites.

  * Except where we are required or permitted by law to share your personal information, you have the right to instruct us not to share your personal information. You also have the right to instruct us not to share information about your creditworthiness among our affiliates. For more information on these privacy choices, see the “Privacy Notices” link above. If you choose to receive email messages from our sites, we may periodically send you email messages describing updates, new features or promotional offers. If you do not explicitly choose to receive informational emails, the only email messages you will receive from us will be in response to email inquiries that you send us.

At any time, you can “opt-out” of receiving direct mail and marketing material from Mutual of Omaha, such as product and service updates, by following the instructions included in your email or by sending a reply stating your request, and we will make the requested changes.

  * Unless otherwise specified, our sites are not directed toward children. We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that personal information on a child under the age of 13 is collected, we will delete that information from our systems.

  * The security of your personal information is very important to us, and we are committed to protecting the information we collect. We have security measures in place that seek to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that Mutual of Omaha has collected from you through our sites.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100 percent secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Mutual of Omaha cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our products or services, and you do so at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the sites.

  * By visiting our sites, you are accepting the terms and conditions of this Policy, and we have the right to use your information as described in this Policy.

This Policy applies only with respect to the information that we collect on-line on our sites and not to any information that Mutual of Omaha collects through other methods or sources.

If for some reason you believe that our sites have not adhered to this Policy, please notify us by:

    * Sending an e-mail request to [webmaster@mutualofomaha.com](mailto:webmaster@mutualofomaha.com); or
    * Sending a letter via US Mail to:  Mutual of Omaha Insurance Company   
3300 Mutual of Omaha Plaza   
Omaha, NE 68175   
Attention: Web Master 
  * Mutual of Omaha reserves the right to modify or amend this Policy at any time. Your continued use of our sites after we post any changes to this Policy on our sites will constitute your acceptance of those changes, so please check the Policy periodically for updates.

The latest revision to this Policy occurred in May, 2015. Changes to this Policy will not affect our use of previously provided personal information.

  * Your use of this site is subject to certain Terms and Conditions of Use. 
  * Please note that whenever you submit any information to us in connection with any Mutual of Omaha products and services, you consent to Mutual of Omaha’s processing of this information as necessary to provide the products and services in which you are participating. 

If you have any questions or comments about our Policy and/or the way it affects you, please feel free to contact us by:

    * Sending an e-mail request to [webmaster@mutualofomaha.com](mailto:webmaster@mutualofomaha.com); or
    * Sending a letter via US Mail to:  Mutual of Omaha Insurance Company   
3300 Mutual of Omaha Plaza   
Omaha, NE 68175   
Attention: Web Master
